<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>The Mountain's Silhouette - The Islands</title><link href="https://tms.invertedworld.co.uk/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://tms.invertedworld.co.uk/feeds/the-islands.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://tms.invertedworld.co.uk/</id><updated>2010-09-12T21:38:40+01:00</updated><subtitle>Hiking and backpacking in the mountains of Scotland</subtitle><entry><title>Bruach na Frithe</title><link href="https://tms.invertedworld.co.uk/blog/2010/09/bruach-na-frithe/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2010-09-12T21:38:40+01:00</published><updated>2010-09-12T21:38:40+01:00</updated><author><name>Nick Bramhall</name></author><id>tag:tms.invertedworld.co.uk,2010-09-12:/blog/2010/09/bruach-na-frithe/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distance: 14.34km&lt;br&gt;
Ascent: 914m&lt;br&gt;
Time: 5hrs 07mins&lt;br&gt;
Munros: Bruach na Frithe (958m)&lt;br&gt;
Weather: Early light rain giving way to sunshine, very strong winds on top&lt;br&gt;
Route: &lt;a href="https://www.invertedworld.co.uk/hillwalking/hillwalk/147"&gt;View on OS Maps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"The Cuillin... they will never look the same for very long, now blue, now grey, now silver, sometimes seeming to retreat or to advance, but always drenched in mystery and terrors"&lt;/em&gt; -- H. V. Morton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993760093"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4151/4993760093_b7f57c8c6a_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Distance: 14.34km&lt;br&gt;
Ascent: 914m&lt;br&gt;
Time: 5hrs 07mins&lt;br&gt;
Munros: Bruach na Frithe (958m)&lt;br&gt;
Weather: Early light rain giving way to sunshine, very strong winds on top&lt;br&gt;
Route: &lt;a href="https://www.invertedworld.co.uk/hillwalking/hillwalk/147"&gt;View on OS Maps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;"The Cuillin... they will never look the same for very long, now blue, now grey, now silver, sometimes seeming to retreat or to advance, but always drenched in mystery and terrors"&lt;/em&gt; -- H. V. Morton&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993760093"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4151/4993760093_b7f57c8c6a_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It is now &lt;a href="/blog/2008/06/skye-weekend/"&gt;more than two years since&lt;/a&gt;, in the company of members of the Stocket Hillwalking Club, I clung, half terrified, half exhilarated, to the shattered black gabbro on the spine of the Black Cuillin of Skye. That day, after an ascent through Coire Lagan, seven hours on the ridge, and then a thrilling final clamber down An Dorus (the door) I had come back to sea level feeling more tired than I had ever felt, but also more satisfied. It had been a testing day, with every move counting as hands and feet found secure holds perched over 3,000ft of empty space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994345596"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4089/4994345596_bc275fd0f9_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was therefore with some trepidation that I embarked on my own today for a climb in the Black Cuillin. The only one of the Munros I could conceive of doing solo was Bruach na Frithe and so it was that I parked up along the Dunvegan road, just west of the Sligachan Hotel. The morning had an air of bright promise with rays of light showering the nearby Red Cuillin. Meanwhile the Black Cuillin, dominating my southern view, were swathed in a maelstrom of cloud that was billowing off the inner sea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993743981"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4133/4993743981_45562ba901_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I set off up the clear vehicle track that leads to the wonderfully picturesque Alltdearg House. Here a helpful sign points you west onto the track that leads towards a low bealach and on into Glen Brittle some five miles distant. The path follows the course of the Allt Dearg Mor which tumbles in a series of delightful rapids and waterfalls down from the feet of the Cuillin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994356170"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4103/4994356170_67eaa21699_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a wonderful walk, particularly as for the most part I was bathed in glorious sunshine. The red hills were visible and as time passed the Black Cuillin gradually shed their early covering of cloud. Initially clouds haunted the pinnacles of Sgurr nan Gillean but as I advanced west, turning the corner, the ridge line itself became clearer. Next up was the corner that would reveal Bruach na Frithe, which is hidden in the view from Sligachan by Sgurr a' Bhasteir but is eventually revealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994376918"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4146/4994376918_2db27de0af_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994369574"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4154/4994369574_71302e6929_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993778025"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4144/4993778025_45e2cf0d0d_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the path approached the summit of the pass a branch headed off to the south, crossing the burn and then starting the climb up into the Fionn Coire which sits below Am Basteir. I followed this for a short distance before turning off to the right and climbing scree slopes. My intended route was up Bruach na Frithe's northeast ridge which hopefully would offer some good scrambling without being too committing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994379562"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4124/4994379562_cf3c49c735_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994425924"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4091/4994425924_e1259031db_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had caught and passed a couple of other people by this point but everyone else on the route seemed to be sticking to the straightforward coire approach. Meanwhile I quickly gained height on the steep, grassy lower slopes of the ridge. The way was easy going with the views beginning to open up despite the swirling cloud. To my right I could follow the line of the track as I dropped into Glen Brittle. Above this were the dark, steep slopes of the central Cuillin, the tops still lost in the mist.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993824693"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4108/4993824693_3b2f42d98c_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993856197"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4133/4993856197_52375015a5_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I climbed higher though things gradually improved with the shapes at the head of the Fionn Coire resolving into distinct shapes, the Basteir tooth clear visible. I also took the time to admire the views that had opened up behind me: to the north and west the sunshine over Dunvegan and to the east over Sligachan and Glamaig. After this though I packed away the camera as now the ridge narrowed and became increasingly rocky as I neared the shoulder of Bruach na Frithe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994459938"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4105/4994459938_7a4e1c8a29_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993822847"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4145/4993822847_680f985fdd_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993858643"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4131/4993858643_d18cd0baf2_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I started to climb the cloud swept in on a chill wind that I had, up until now, largely been sheltered from. It at least allowed me to concentrate on my route which took my up a series of shattered terraces close to the line of the ridge. After this it flattened out somewhat and became a fine walk, made a little interesting by the buffeting wind. I was once again treated to some fine views before I reached the final steep climb up to the summit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993860965"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4131/4993860965_1c1be62db8_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993871433"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4105/4993871433_1307b1f091_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was once again plunged into cloud. At the steep section I followed a distinct path that kept well below and to the right of the ridge-line, now a tumbling series of black rocks. Finally though the track petered out and I took to a gully that climbed rapidly up. After that a second gully ended in a chockstone that forced me out and to the left, back up to the ridge. I paused here as a gap in the swirling clouds gave me views back down the ridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994480740"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4124/4994480740_78b4bae6ff_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994483046"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4092/4994483046_48b0962876_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994485830"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4131/4994485830_ae2b80621f_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was now a final interesting section up another gully which had to be turned to the right before I once again hit on a clear track that rallied itself and now headed straight for the summit of the mountain. I emerged slightly breathless but elated just to the southeast of the trig point - one of the few on the Cuillin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994493542"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4104/4994493542_9673c9a8df_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994495660"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4131/4994495660_d3aaf05550_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994503384"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4089/4994503384_34ce95a692_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The clouds had kept back for this moment and as another couple who had come up from the Coire joined me, we were able to enjoy extensive views all around. Only the southern bulk of the Cuillin remained stubbornly in the mist. Despite this there were views across to Blaven and Loch Scavaig as well as closer at hand, to Am Basteir and Sgurr nan Gillean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994505926"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4089/4994505926_93e8fa1cd1_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993901511"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4088/4993901511_cdee6d8076_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was a fantastic sight that gave a thrilling feel of vertigo amongst these steep, ragged spires of dark rock. The monochrome effect of so much grey and black rock makes you feel like you have stepped out of a spaceship door onto an alien world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993891107"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4131/4993891107_4196fc2530_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994390982"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4124/4994390982_684a024b6c_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I spent a good half an hour on the summit, enjoying a bite of lunch and drinking some water. Unfortunately the views deteriorated during this period until I was eventually shrouded in a cold, clammy mist. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994525440"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4090/4994525440_5da105ba40_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although I had a few choices from here, given the weather that was rapidly closing in, I decided to take the sensible route off the mountain and follow the coire track back to the Allt Dearg Mor track. Given a bit more time an interesting route from here might have been to head to the summit of Sgurr a' Bhasteir and then drop off the east side of the hill towards the Bhasteir gorge and the track back to Sligachan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993908413"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4106/4993908413_b39597e1b5_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994520484"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4083/4994520484_d8b6931061_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead I dropped down the east ridge of Bruach na Frithe (the easy Munro bagger route of ascent) and followed a rough track below Sgurr a' Fhionn Coire, a rough toppled table of rock, until I got an intimidating view of Am Basteir and the Basteir Tooth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993929373"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4149/4993929373_d684920e60_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994538328"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4085/4994538328_0b300a72d4_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ground here is rough and so after peering down towards the south-eastern arm of Sgurr nan Gillean I tracked some way along the ridge towards Sgurr a' Bhasteir. At the low point on the ridge I then dropped to the left down rough scree to join the main track through Fionn Coire. From the ridge I got some great views back to Am Basteir and witness the echoing cry of a rook as it perched just below the tooth. In the misty, grey-black world it was a lonely and forbidding sound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993933703"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4106/4993933703_19451c566f_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993937629"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4148/4993937629_bcb3f40490_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994547606"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4128/4994547606_c8c80de59c_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993956391"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4144/4993956391_95e91bb281_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On a good track that dropped through the gently sloping coire I made excellent progress, soon dipping below the gradually building cloud until I was following a tumbling allt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993953637"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4148/4993953637_718387acfa_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994565350"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4085/4994565350_cc8ee6cc6d_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993964807"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4110/4993964807_3480252efe_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a while the track faded into the general scree and rubble at the wide entrance to the coire. I tracked across to the left, crossed a rapidly running stream by some rocks and joined a track that would eventually lead me to my outward path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Down the course of the Allt Dearg Mor and shower had come in from the west and now caused a semi bright rainbow to form over Sligachan. Behind me it was clear heavier rain was rapidly moving in (as forecast by the BBC that morning) and so I got a move on, re-crossing the stream and quickly taking the path back out to my waiting car. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994575522"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4149/4994575522_167ee61986_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4993971257"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4132/4993971257_54d6b0bb17_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994580034"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4126/4994580034_013ae8963f_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I passed the house at Alltdearg and got a last look at the Cuillin the first rain drops splashed off my coat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/4994591694"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="http://farm5.static.flickr.com/4087/4994591694_d2ddc55eb1_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I threw my boots and sack in the boot of the car and got inside just as the rain really started to build. I had timed it to perfection, getting up and down a Skye Munro in just over five hours. The rain that was just starting now would continue for the next 36 hours!&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Skye Weekend</title><link href="https://tms.invertedworld.co.uk/blog/2008/06/skye-weekend/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2008-06-02T20:36:39+01:00</published><updated>2008-06-02T20:36:39+01:00</updated><author><name>Nick Bramhall</name></author><id>tag:tms.invertedworld.co.uk,2008-06-02:/blog/2008/06/skye-weekend/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Day 1 - The Drive West and Glamaig&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aberdeen was shrouded in cloud as we headed down the A90 on the first stage of the journey to Skye. A subsequent damp stop in Dunkeld (where we stumbled upon a flower show in the Cathedral) was followed by a drive up the busy A9 between mountains that became increasingly higher and wilder.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Day 1 - The Drive West and Glamaig&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aberdeen was shrouded in cloud as we headed down the A90 on the first stage of the journey to Skye. A subsequent damp stop in Dunkeld (where we stumbled upon a flower show in the Cathedral) was followed by a drive up the busy A9 between mountains that became increasingly higher and wilder.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The first signs of sunshine came as we stopped above Loch Laggan, shortly before the route took us up the Great Glen alongside Loch Lochy. After being almost run over by the local Laird at Spean Bridge, and stopping for hugely expensive diesel in Invergarry, the clouds once again rolled in as we passed Loch Cluanie, then Glen Shiel. Passing through Kintail, with the Five Sisters behind us, the waters of Loch Duich turned blue and the sun streamed out, illuminating the distant Skye Bridge, behind which the great jagged ridge of the Cuillins could be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/black_friction/2546220630/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Loch Alsh, the Bridge and Skye" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2149/2546220630_8f1f7f502f_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was only a short drive then to Kyle of Lochalsh, over the now toll-free Bridge, and onto the Island itself. A half hour of driving took us around the coast to Loch Sligachan with its head a riot of colour as the Sligachan campsite came into view close to the Hotel, bridge, and our bunkhouse close under the distinctive cone of Glamaig.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After negotiating a set of keys, unloading the car and changing into walking attire we headed off up, initially unsure of our exact route, towards Glamaig. At 775m it is one of two Corbetts on the island. Initially we followed boggy, fairly level ground which skirted the western slopes of the hill, heading around to the Bealach south-east of the summit. Ascending a ridge it became clear this way would be just as difficult as a direct ascent of the steep sided mountain so we abandoned it, crossed a stream and headed up towards the summit. It was a along and arduous climb, sticking to the grassier areas and avoiding the screes and boulders where possible. A good hour or so brought us from nearly sea level up to the 758m high summit where the ground mercifully levelled off and the views opened up spectacularly all around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/black_friction/2546419728/"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Red Cuillin of Skye" src="http://farm3.static.flickr.com/2175/2546419728_3330f77c60_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We chose a more direct descent, sticking to the grass again where possible and heading for the hotel. It was again very steep and the knees took a jarring but before too long we had reached the road and walked back towards the bunkhouse. The low sun on the Cuillin was quite a sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/black_friction/2545502211/"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Northern Cuillin" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3258/2545502211_c32925e61a_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 2 - The Black Cuillin&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Following various discussions the previous night I joined up with Linda, Alison, Margriet and Christopher for an ambitious day in the Cuillins. Besides the campsite at Glen Brittle, our starting point, Chris remarked that it was to be something of a Baptism of Fire. He wasn’t wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The morning had started with Skye shrouded in thick mist but as we drove around the island to Glen Brittle the jagged tops of the Cuillin suddenly appeared wraithlike from between the clouds. Within seconds the mantle had been brushed away like cobwebs. Before us, under brilliant blue skies was the Cuillin Hills, the jagged Black Cuillin of Skye and some of the most spectacular and challenging hillwalking in the United Kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/black_friction/2545774033/"&gt;&lt;img alt="P1150448_b.jpg" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3105/2545774033_fb052f901a_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite their apparent proximity it was a still a long, hot trek up a good path from the campsite to Coire Lagan with its lochan surrounded by great slabs of Gabbro. Just below the Lochan we stopped and scrambled across to a waterfall to refill our water bottles – they were already being quickly emptied and we wouldn’t see any more water until we climbed down from An Dorus several hours later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Coire was already fairly busy with several groups heading off at different angles up the screes. We chose a route over to the left of the Coire, away from the worst of the screes and where possible following the firmer rocks as they climbed up towards Am Stac. Across the way we could see the route up the Great Stone Chute to Sgurr Alasdair, as well as the other magnificent peaks that looked down upon the Lochan. Those with a less strenuous day were soaking up the sun next to its algeaed waters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/black_friction/2546654946/"&gt;&lt;img alt="Loch Coire Lagan" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3101/2546654946_0afcba7539_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At a point just below the Bealach between Sgurr Dearg and Sgurr Mhic Choinnich we left our bags, and free of the weight started to make our way right and up towards the latter of these two peaks. Nothing can prepare you for the first time you reach the actual ridge and my lower jaw plunged as I topped the crest. The whole breathtaking panorama opened wide in front of me like nothing I had ever seen before. Peak after peak plunging down in inconceivably steep sides to the green glen below. There wasn't too much time to enjoy the view as we now started the scramble and concentration was fully on where feet and hands were going. This was for me the most demanding part of the day I don't my head was yet in the right place and I was finding things tough going. I made it up some of the difficult ledges but then we came out again on a very exposed part which led to the last climb up onto the summit. It was at this point where my feet refused to move onwards and i found myself clutching at the ridgeline and no way of moving forward. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there I watched the three others (one had come short a little way before me) make it up to the summit which was only a minute or so further scramble from where I had stopped. It had certainly been an interesting first taste of the Cuillins, but I wasn't put off just yet and even the scramble down back to our bags seemed easier than it had appeared going up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once back to the point below the Bealach we paused to eat lunch, watching as more walkers toiled up the Stone Chute, whilst others celebrated on the top of Sgurr Alasdair. As we were packing up our bags the unrelenting sunshine was dimmed by a patch of cloud that had moved in from the west, now partially obscuring the top of the peaks opposite. In the slightly cooler air we now made our way carefully up the slopes behind us, eventually coming up and around the base of the infamous &lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/black_friction/2546667680/in/set-72157605373811424/"&gt;Inaccessible Pinnacle&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There seemed to be climbers all over this dramatic fin of rock, which we could appreciate only once we had made it to the lesser summit of Sgurr Dearg. All around us the peaks of the ridge could be seen continuing northwards. This is the route we would take.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From Sgurr Dearg it was easier walking dropping slightly below the ridge and making our way across to the next Munro. The flanks of Sgurr na Banachdich were well defended but my body was acclimatising much better to the exposure and scrambling and it wasn't long before we pulled ourself up onto the top. We now had magnificent views all around, particular down towards Loch Coruisk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/2553734641"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cuillin and Loch Coruisk" src="http://static.flickr.com/3119/2553734641_2a5cd34c1d_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We descended from Banachdich and made our way along towards the next Munro. Climbing here was steep and tricky and we first of all failed to find a way around Sgurr Thomaid which is a top sticking out of the ridge. Down this we descended and then followed the ridge up to the south top of Sgurr a'Ghreadaidh. From here to the summit it was a crawl along the knife-edged arete. It was terrifying but the satisfaction gained by reaching the summit was incomparable. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From here we had stunning views all around, down to Loch Coruisk far below, and away to the Outer Hebrides. The combination of mountain, sea and sun was incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/2546708636"&gt;&lt;img alt="View north along the Cuillin Ridge" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3081/2546708636_4ee8178428_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now followed the ridge down, bypassing the Wart on its easier right hand side and coming down towards An Dorus (the Door). This is a notch in the ridge which allows a safe descent down to Glen Brittle. The last few metres were across smooth slabs and then a final plunge down an 8 foot rock wall which we were helpfully guided down after throwing our bags down!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was now a simple task of descending the screes below An Dorus to where the path met the stream met at the bottom of Coire An Dorus. We spent time washing faces and drinking the beautifully clear mountain water. The walk out of Coire An Dorus gradually hid the hills behind us and soon enough we came out past an impressive waterfall to the Youth Hostel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It had been almost ten hours since we left the cars at the campsite but the day had been thrilling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Day 3 - Bla Bheinn (Blaven)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A slightly later start saw us heading through Torrin and around the head of Loch Slapin to the start of the main track up to Blaven. Again the skies were clearest blue and the initial walk, besides the gorge and its chattering scream was delightful. After the second river crossing the ascent started on a much eroded path up to the head of Coire Uaigneich and the delightful grassy alp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/2553741701"&gt;&lt;img alt="Blaven" src="http://static.flickr.com/2381/2553741701_ec075f8719_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I continued on my own, picking a way up the right stone buttress and following a steep but clear track that wound its way up the mountain. Every so often a great crack would appear with dizzying views down to the glens far below. The last part took me up a delightful tumble of boulders which provided easy scrambling. From there it was only a few minutes up to the summit where I found the cairn and trig point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The view over to the Cuillin was breathtaking and I sat right on the very edge facing them as I ate my lunch. Other climbers arrived and remarked on the excellent weather.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.flickr.com/photos/53725815@N00/2548901622"&gt;&lt;img alt="Towards the Cuillin" src="http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3260/2548901622_555bdbc348_b.jpg"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I followed a slightly different course down to the Coire and finally descended to the stream where I waited for Gordon to join me. It was then a quick march back to the car and all too soon it was time to leave Skye.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The good weather lasted until the head of Glen Shiel after which we lost the sunshine and were met by increasingly heavy clouds until, just beyond Inverness the rain met us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arriving back in Aberdeen and running to avoid the rain it seemed like the weekend on Skye had been in a different time. It was a very special experience and I can't wait to return.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="corbett"></category><category term="munro"></category></entry></feed>